What killed the dinosaurs?
Ice Age: Dawn of the Dinosaurs is a animation, comedy,
family film directed by Carlos Saldanha.
Times are changing for Manny the moody mammoth, Sid the motor
mouthed sloth and Diego the crafty saber-toothed tiger.
Life heats up for our heroes when they meet some new and
none-too-friendly neighbors – the mighty dinosaurs.
Manny (voice), played by Ray Romano.
Sid (voice), played by John Leguizamo.
Diego (voice), played by Denis Leary.
Ellie (voice), played by Queen Latifah.
Buck (voice), played by Simon Pegg.
Crash (voice), played by Seann William Scott.
Ice Age: Dawn of the Dinosaurs is a 2009 American animated
adventure comedy film produced by Blue Sky Studios.
The third in the Ice Age film series, it was directed by Carlos Saldanha, and
written by Michael Berg, Peter Ackerman, Mike Reiss, and Yoni Brenner.
John Leguizamo, Ray Romano and Denis Leary reprise their roles from the first two
films and Queen Latifah reprises her role from the second film.
In the film, while Manny and Ellie are preparing for their baby, Sid the Sloth is kidnapped by a female Tyrannosaurus after stealing
her eggs, leading the rest of the herd to rescue him in a tropical lost world inhabited by dinosaurs underneath the ice.
Ice Age: Dawn of the Dinosaurs was released on July 1, 2009 by 20th Century Fox.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for
its animation but criticism for the story.
The film grossed $887 million worldwide, becoming the
third-highest-grossing film and the highest-grossing animated film of 2009.
It was followed by two further sequels, Ice Age: Continental
Drift in 2012 and Ice Age: Collision Course in 2016.
The film explores themes of insanity, ice age, villain, bridge, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted.